Jamie Pantazi Esmond, MPP

I am a recent graduate of the Andrew Young School of Policy Studies at Georgia State University. Before completing this master's program, I worked for several years in the Family Detention Department of RAICES, analyzing and organizing data collected from our detained clients. I am passionate about research, data, and advocacy. I have experience working with issues such as immigration, prison abolition, and peer-led mental health support. I hope to continue my work using data to advocate for communities struggling against systemic oppression.

EXPERIENCE

Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA

Graduate Research/Teaching Assistant/Graduate Student IANUARY 2022 - DECEMBER 2023

Conducted research and organized data for large projects. Utilized coding, including automation, for extensive data collection. Completed independent research utilizing multiple methods and software. Supported student discussion and understanding of concepts. Utilized advanced methodologies for research including Bayesian statistical models.

RAICES, Family Detention Department, San Antonio, TX

Data Analysis Unit Coordinator

JANUARY 2019 - JANUARY 2022

Organized and analyzed data regarding detained clients quickly and without error. Composed reports on the data and flagged urgent cases when needed. Collected and presented data, sometimes on very short notice. Organized and delegated work for larger projects. Trained others for accurate data collection, entry, and reporting.

Icarus Project, Atlanta, GA — *Facilitator*

JANUARY 2015 - OCTOBER 2016

Organized, promoted, and led a radical mental health support group. Free and open to all, this organization provided peer support for anyone struggling with any kind of mental health issues or concerns.

EDUCATION

Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA— *Bachelor of Arts in History* IANUARY 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

Maintained a 4.0 GPA, summa cum laude graduate, Phi Alpha Theta President.

Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA— *Master of Public Policy*

JANUARY 2022 - DECEMBER 2023

Concentration in policy analytics, maintained a 4.0 GPA, held a graduate research assistantship and a teaching assistantship.

PROJECTS

<u>Karnes Family Immigration Prison as an Adult Immigration Prison: Why</u>
<u>Expedited Removal and Immigrant Detention Must End</u> — July 2022

Willing to Relocate

7940 Praver Dr W Jacskonville, FL 32217 **(904) 742-7662**

jamie.pantazi@gmail.com www.jamiepantazi.com

SKILLS

Research and analysis

Critical thinking

Attention to detail

Organization and time management

Data visualization and report writing

Written and oral communication

Data-driven impact evaluation

Data analytics:
GIS / R / SQL / Python /
NVivo / STATA / AI /
Machine Learning

Microsoft Office / Google Suite

Passion for helping others

AWARDS

Henry Thompson Malone Memorial Scholarship - 2018

Michael Mescon Public Service Leadership Scholarship - 2022

REFERENCES

Dr. Andrew Heiss, Andrew Young School of Policy Studies, GSU

Andrea Meza, formerly RAICES

Emeline Renz, Urban Studies Institute, GSU